⊕ pmsg21.github.io

Phone Number: +351 914 578 268

E-mail: pmsg21@gmail.com

Location: Portugal (resident)

Open to relocate

Languages: Spanish (Native) English (B2)

For my future I would like to continue developing on the frontend using libraries like React, learning new ways to structure code, and to use new technologies that will enrich the quality of my work and allow me to lead and support different teams and projects.

I'm a web developer with 6+ years of experience working with legal, insurance and security oriented companies, collaborating remotely with international teams. Although I have worked as a fullstack I'm currently dedicated to the frontend working with React, applying clean code and the S.O.L.I.D principles in each of my developments.

I have had the opportunity to work with different types of technologies and work methodologies (Scrum, Kanban), which has improved not only my knowledge but also how I interact with my colleagues and how I approach all challenges.

EDUCATION

Systems Engineer

Universidad Bicentenaria de Aragua (U.B.A) / 2011 - 2017

WORK EXPERIENCE

— React Developer

Company: Webdox CLM / Portugal (remote) / 2022 - 2023

I worked on the development and maintenance of a web application for a Contract Lifecycle Management (CLM) using React and TypeScript. The application aimed to digitally manage commercial contracts through all stages, from creation to storage. I was part of a multidisciplinary team that included a Product Manager, a Product Designer, Engineering Managers, and both backend and frontend developers. We adopted agile methodologies like Scrum and Kanban to enhance efficiency and collaboration in the project, with 2-week sprints for task planning and execution. Some of these tasks included:

- · Developing different sections of the application, in which I:
 - Added a new functionality that mitigated a significant security issue related to user password management.
 - Created a settings section that allows the enabling/disabling and permissions management of an important product feature.
 - Implemented a feature that restricts the types of documents the application allows, resulting in the product's security optimization.
- Developing several components in the design system using Storybook, rigorously tested, which were subsequently integrated into the product, applying the necessary logic so that other developers could use them, which managed, for example, to prevent a considerable security risk regarding excessive resource usage.
- · Refactoring legacy components to eliminate technical debt and improve the application's performance.

React.js TypeScript JavaScript react-testing-library	Jest	react-query
HTML5 CSS3 SASS Storybook Design System Git		

— Full-Stack Developer

Company: Initium Software / Venezuela / 2020 - 2022

I participated in the development and maintenance of a web application for an insurance company, using JavaScript, jQuery, and Symfony. The purpose was to enable quoting and management of information related to the services offered by the insurance company. I was part of a team that included a Product Manager, an Engineering Manager, and full-stack developers. We applied Scrum as an agile methodology, with one-week sprints. During my involvement, I carried out various tasks, including:

- Developing a functionality that generates quotes based on the information provided by the user.
- · Creating an informative section about the insurance's functionality.
- · Creating multiple REST services for CRUD operations of different records in the database.

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript jQuery	Bootstrap 4 Symfony 4 PHP AJAX REST APIs
(Angular 9) (Postman) (Twig Template	es Git

— Full-Stack Developer

Company: Technology 4 Solutions / OUSA (remote) / 2018 - 2020

I contributed to the development and maintenance of a web application designed for monitoring, security, and registration of buses and students on a school route, using AngularJS and CakePHP. I was part of a team consisting of four developers and one designer. Some of the tasks I carried out included:

- · Collaborating in the development of an application that allowed the GPS tracking of vehicles and users of a school route.
- · Implementing a functionality that obtained the historical record of the routes of a vehicle or driver, drawing polylines on a map according to the coordinates of the vehicle.
- · Creating a desktop application that connected with previously developed web services, allowing efficient record creation and editing.
- · Creating and modifying web services and performing unit and integration tests on them.
- · Creating Stored Procedures for the database.



— Full-Stack Developer

Company: Soluciones Medianet / OVenezuela / 2017 - 2018

- · In charge of the development of a responsive informative website.
- · Restructured and developed (fullstack) new sections of a web application for an insurance company.
- · Responsible for updating and creating records, tables and scripts for the database.
- · Dictated a 1 week course about how to maintain the developed application.



PROJECTS

— Shanelle Productions LLC (2022-Ongoing) ®USA (remote) ⊕shanelleproductions.com

- · Developed an informative website with a responsive, interactive and multilanguage design.
- · Hosting configuration and website deployment.



MAIN COURSES

- React PRO: Take your foundations to the next level // Udemy // September 2023
- S.O.L.I.D principles and Clean Code // Udemy // June 2022
- TypeScript: your complete guide and handbook // Udemy // March 2020
- JavaScript: ECMAScript 6 and all its details // Udemy // February 2020